嗯。
立法會主席。
Thank you, Mr. President.
在2017。
on behalf of the Public Accounts Committee.
我有榮耀將我們的報告號碼71A。
The first report, which focus on another related chapter.
More than 50% of which was spent on the import control of foods.
Over ninety percent of foods and live food animals for human consumption.
Is on the management of food safety was tabled in the council in February this year.
This is the committee's second report on the director of audits report number seventy one.
import control is of paramount importance to ensuring effective food safety control in Hong Kong.
發言，石禮謙議員就政府帳目委員會第七十一A號報告書向本會發言，石禮謙議。
它 contains our conclusions and recommendations on the chapter of the Centre for Food Safety, import control of foods.
在香港，were imported. According to the government's published trade statistics, the total value of imported goods in 2017 was more than 200 billion.
在過去五年，開支於食物安全中心（食物安全中心，簡稱CFS）的經費，已由44800萬增至59200萬，增加32%。
and and the operation manual.
fail to ensure their front-line staff compliant.
One example, as reviewed by the audit commission.
The committee also considered that CFS management and supervisory staff have.
Various problems and shortcomings could not be addressed timely and effectively.
數字
The committee also expresses grave dismay and finds it unacceptable that the CFS has.
Guidelines and operation manual have been prepared to assist CFS staff in carrying out their duties.
not proactively reviewed its practices, system and the operation manual to identify the deficiencies.
在一 serious case， which is still under investigation by CFS， or the commit commission reviewed that in five inspections on food samples imported by air。
CFS set up food control offices across the territory to carry out established procedures for controlling the import of foods via air, road and sea.
The food samples were pre-selected for radiation test by importers. This is contrary to the guideline that the sample should be randomly selected by the CFS staff.
The committee urges the CFS to set up a mechanism to review the workflow at various food control offices in order to identify whether they could achieve their intended purposes and are practical.
The committee expresses grave dismay and finds it unacceptable that the CFS staff had not followed the established procedures in the import control of foods, as evidenced by a number of incidents reviewed in the audit report.
was the evasion of inspection by vehicles at Mangado Food Control Office. Audit Commission discovered that nine vehicles had at least once evaded CFS inspection at the control office, and two vehicles have never been driven.
into the control office of the CFS inspection of the consignments of these vehicles. It was further discovered that seven vehicles which had actually entered the control office were not shown in the CFS inspection records because their vehicle registration
專營的士服務條例重。
政府法案首讀。
hard work. Thank you, Mr. President.
as soon as possible.
support. Lastly, I like to thank the secretary for their
Our gratitude to the director of audit and his colleague for their unfailing.
lastly, I wish to record my appreciation of the contribution made by members of the community.
Our gratitude also goes to the witnesses who attended the hearing, help body committee. I would like to express
The committee notes that CFS has created a time-limited post of senior principal executive officer in 2017 for a period of seven years to head a dedicated team to take forward the recasting and re-engineering of workflow and the.
over all and overall of information technology system to substantially strengthen in data management and analysis for food safety control. In this regard, the committee urges CFS to make good use of this new dedicated.
The team to conduct a comprehensive review to rationalise and simplify the workflows associated with the import control of food. The work of the dedicated team should be expedited, and any recommendations made by the team should be implemented.